JORGEN BAERTSCH

🗣 SEATTLE, WA, US 🗷 jpbaertsch@gmail.com 🛘 +1(218) 348-8032 🗖 https://www.linkedin.com/in/jorgen-baertsch-8673b2142/ ぬ https://jpbaer.github.io/React-Portfolio/

SUMMARY

As a highly skilled full-stack software engineer with 3 years of experience in aerospace systems, I bring a unique blend of technical expertise and problem-solving skills to any project. With proficiency in multiple programming languages, including Python and JavaScript frameworks such as Node.Js, MongoDB and React, I am equipped to deliver cutting-edge solutions that exceed expectations.

EXPERIENCE

Recording/Mixing Engineer

Lost Boys Studios

August 2021 - Present, US, WA, Seattle

- · Utilize a wide variety of hardware and software devices to record, edit, and mix audio to provide client's with a professional song that meets and exceeds industry expectations.
- · Troubleshoot and resolve issues with recording hardware and software.

Aerospace Systems Engineer

Left Hand Design

June 2018 - March 2021, US, CO, Longmont

- · Aided in the development, procurement, and sale of Fast-Steering Mirrors for use in laser communication and defense systems.
- Interfaced with customers to answer requests for information, develop system requirements, price tables and proposals leading in the generation of multiple contracts ranging from \$500,000 to \$5 million dollars.
- · Maintained assembly travelers and performed tests to ensure critical design requirements were being met.

PROJECTS

Project Manager/Backend Lead - Climate Change Impact App

- · Managed tasks and timelines for a team of 4 to develop a carbon footprint calculator that utilizes JavaScript, Node.JS, React, MongoDB, and GraphQL.
- \cdot Created GraphQL typeDefs and resolvers to define queries for retrieving user information and mutations for updating users carbon impacts based on various inputs.
- · Pulled data from MongoDB database and displayed it graphically using Chart.JS.
- · Incorporated a GPT chatbot on the applications "Learn" page using OpenAI API.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Created reusable UX/UI components for profile, learn and home pages

Project Manager/Backend Lead - Music Sharing Social Media App March 2023 - March 2023

- · Successfully built application using Node. Js and SQL that integrates Spotify API our own REST API and database to pull and display users listening habits and playlists in social media like feed.
- · Developed feature for authentication, unique user profiles, messaging between users, and like and comment functionality.
- · Managed team of 4 using agile methodology for timelines and task delegation.

Project Manager/Backend Lead - Real Estate App

February 2023 - February 2023

- · Developed a website using Javascript's Node. Js that utilizes an external real estate API to search cities and display current houses for sale.
- · Lead the integration of geo-location data from Google Maps API to fetch data from the real estate API at users location.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Science In Aerospace Engineering

University of Colorado at Boulder · US, Colorado, Boulder · 2018

CERTIFICATIONS

Full Stack Development Certification

EdEx Bootcamps via University of Washington • 2023

Primary Skills Gained: React, NodeJs, SQL, MongoDB, Express, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Graph Developer - Associate

Apollo GraphQL · 2023

GraphQL Queries and Mutations, GraphQL Resolvers, GraphQL TypeDefs, React.JS

SKILLS

JavaScript, Node.JS, SQL, MongoDB, React, UI/UX, HTML, CSS, Python, Git, REST API Development, GraphQL, Data Structures, Algorithms, System Design, Project Management, Docker, Jest, Debugging, Data Engineering, MVC, Microsoft Office